Finding Aid for Dept. of Materials Science and Engineering (University of Michigan) publications, 1971-1991
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dept. of Materials Science and Engineering (University of Michigan) publications 1971-1991 1986-1991
University of Michigan. Dept. of Materials Science and Engineering.
0.2 linear feet
9715 Bimu C146 2
Department in the University of Michigan College of Engineering, includes brochures and pamphlets, bulletins describing the graduate programs, and bibliographies of faculty members.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The publications are received periodically from the College of Engineering (donor no. 1884 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
A department of the College of Engineering of the University of Michigan, Materials Science and Engineering (MSE) covers scientific and engineering principles as well as their application to realistic problems. In developing these principles, students use chemistry and physics to understand how properties of materials depend on chemical bonding, atomic and molecular arrangements, crystal structures, and microstructures. The department offers both undergraudaute and graduate degrees.
The Department of Materials Science Engineering Publications (0.2 linear foot) are divided into two series: Unit Publications, Sub-Unit Publications, Topical Publications and Student Publications. The bulk of the publications document Department of Materials Science Engineering.
The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the Department of Materials Science Engineering. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication.
The Unit Publications series includes brochures, bulletins, manuals, and reports. The bulletins describe graduate study at the university from 1956 to 1994. The bulletin describing the research done in the MSE department includes a short, select bibliography for each member of the department in 1974. The graduate students manuals written for the 1990-1991 academic year includes a directory of personnel in the department, a description of the research facilities, and degree requirements. The 1954 report, A Year in Industry by Professor C.M. Sliepcevich, describes his impressions of the year he worked with the Monsanto Chemical Company.
The Sub-Unit Publications series contains publications from subordinate offices, departments, programs and organizations within the Department of Materials Science Engineering. These publications are arranged alphabetically by the creating sub-unit. These publications include a list of faculty and their work with professional organizations and various industrial companies.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Dept. of Materials Science and Engineering.
Genre Terms:
Bibliographies.; Bulletins.; Pamphlets.
- Unit Publications
  - Brochures, 1956-1994 (Box 1)
  - Bulletins
    - Graduate Study in Materials Science and Engineering, 1971-1994 and undated (Box 1)
    - Research in Materials and Metallurgical Engineering includes Short Bibliography of Individual Faculty Members, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Manuals
    - Graduate Student Handbook, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
    - Reports (Box 1)
    - A Year in Industry by C. M. Sliepcevich, 1954 (Box 1)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  - Outreach
    - Faculty Outreach Activities, 1986 (Box 1)